A Finding Aid to the Douglas Leigh Papers, 1903-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.leigdoug
Archives of American Art
- Billboard Project Files, 1929-1997; Series 10; (Box 1, 6, 14-25, BV 33; 5.0 linear feet)
  - Individual Billboard Product Files, 1936-1980; 10.5
    - Cleopatra Movie Sign, Photographs of Executives Lighting Sign, 1963 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Coca-Cola, Photographs and World's Fair Material, 1963 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Contac Cold Remedy, Photograph, ca. 1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Eveready Batteries, Photographs, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Eveready Batteries, Billboard Scrapbook 22 (see Box 22), 1949-1950 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Flamingo Foods, Photographs, 1951-1952; (7 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - General Electric Iron, Artwork for Billboard, 1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Gordon's Gin/ Haig Scotch Whisky, Photographs, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Grand Union Grocery Store, Photographs, ca. 1955 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Hennessy Cognac, Photographs, 1955 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Kool Cigarettes, Photograph, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Mattel Toys, Photographs, 1964 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Museum of Science and Industry, Photograph, 1944 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Nassau Tourism, Photographs, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - N W Bank, Blueprints of Design for Sign, ca. 1940s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Pepsi-Cola, Scripts for Animation of Pepsi EPOK in Tokyo, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - REM Cold Remedy, Photographs, 1945-1948 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Rheingold Beer, Photographs, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Salem Cigarettes, Notes and Photographs, ca. 1960 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Savarin Coffee, Photograph, ca. 1940s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Schaefer Beer, Photographs, 1945-1947 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Scripto Pens, Photograph and Press Release, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Sunbeam Vacuum Cleaner, Photographs, 1957 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - TDK Recording Tape, Photograph, 1980 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Teacher's Scotch Whisky, Photograph, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Time, Life, Sports Illustrated Magazines, Photographs, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Time, Life, Sports Illustrated Magazines, Billboard Scrapbook 26 (see Box 24), 1957-1958 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - WABC Broadcasting, Photographs, ca. 1940s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - War Bonds, Photographs, ca. 1943 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Wilson Whiskey Photographs, 1940-1942 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Wilson Whiskey Billboard Scrapbook 27 (see Box 24), 1940 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Winston Cigarettes, Photographs, 1974 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - WNBC Broadcasting, Photograph, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - WOR Broadcasting, Photographs, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Wrigley's Gum, Photograph of sign, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
    - Oversize Photograph of Black Horse Ale Sign, 1944 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Oversize Photograph of Bond Clothes Sign, 1949 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Oversize Photograph of Chevrolet Automobiles Sign, n.d. (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Oversize Photographs of Completed Pepsi-Cola Sign, 1955-1958 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Eveready Batteries, Billboard Scrapbook 22, 1949-1950 (Box 22 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Billboard Scrapbook 23, 1955-1956 (Box 22 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Billboard Scrapbook 24, 1945-1948 (Box 23 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Billboard Scrapbook 25, 1945-1947 (Box 23 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Time, Life, Sports Illustrated Magazines, Billboard Scrapbook 26, 1957-1958 (Box 24 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Wilson Whiskey Billboard Scrapbook 27, 1940 (Box 24 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Billboard Scrapbook 28, Aug-Nov 1940 (Box 25 (sol), Reel 5845)
    - Billboard Scrapbook 29, 1941-1942 (Box 25 (sol), Reel 5845)
- Poster Project Files, 1943-1963; Series 11; (Box 7-8, 14; 1.6 linear feet)
  This series consists of notes, reports, artwork, photographs, miscellaneous printed material, 4 scrapbooks, and individual product files that document the development of poster advertising projects, primarily those used on Railway Express Agency delivery trucks that would circulate the poster advertisements throughout urban areas. Individual product files typically contain photographs, notes, clippings, and other printed materials. Although scrapbooks have been consecutively numbered within this series, they either focus on multiple projects or are solely associated with one project and arranged with that project. There is also a file concerning the Shopping Center Network Semaphore Poster Display that involved the placement of hanging posters on light poles in shopping center parking lots.
  - Miscellaneous Notes, ca. 1963 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Report: Consumer Recognition Study of Poster Advertising, 1943 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Report: A Comprehensive Study and Analysis of the REA Express Poster, 1961 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Report: Express Posters U.S.A., 1961 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Artwork for a Poster by Walter Griffin (see also Box 14), 1943 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Miscellaneous Press Releases, 1948, n.d. (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Poster Scrapbook 1, 1954-1963 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - American Dairy Association Poster File, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Amoco Gasoline and Oil Poster File, ca. 1953 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Amoco Gasoline and Oil, Poster Scrapbook 2, 1952-1961 (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Beeline Radio Stations Poster File, California and Nevada, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Black Label Beer, Stag Beer Poster File, ca. 1940s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Blue Cross Poster File, ca. 1940s (Box 7, Reel 5845)
  - Camel Cigarettes, Poster Scrapbook 3, 1943-1947; (5 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5846)
  - Camel Cigarettes, Poster Scrapbook 3, 1943-1947; (8 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Camel Cigarettes, Poster Scrapbook 4, 1948-1956; (15 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Chase and Sanborn Coffee Poster File, 1955 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Flamingo Foods Poster File, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Fram Motor Oil Poster File, 1962 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Hudson Hornet Automobile Poster File, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Lux Soap Poster File, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Museum of Science and Industry Poster File, 1944 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Red Cross Show, Madison Square Garden, Poster File, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - REM Cold Remedy Poster File, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Salem Cigarettes Poster File, 1960 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Twenhoefel's Automobile Insurance Poster File, ca. 1960s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - U. S. Navy (WAVES) Poster File, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - War Bonds Poster File, 1943-1945; (4 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Wearever Pens Poster File, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Winston Cigarettes Poster File, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Shopping Center Network Semaphore Poster Display File, 1960; (3 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Oversize Artwork for a Poster by Walter Griffin, 1943 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5845)
- Dirigible Project Files, 1944-1954; Series 12; (Box 8-11, 14, 26-28; 3.7 linear feet)
  This series consists of notes, reports, artwork, photographs, miscellaneous printed material, 12 scrapbooks, and individual product files that document the development of dirigible advertising projects involving both painted logos and networks of lights over the surface of the dirigible. Sequentially-timed lights caused dramatic animated effects against the night sky. Individual Product/Project Files are arranged alphabetically and typically contain photographs, scrapbooks, printed material, and scattered drawings. Leigh compiled scrapbooks of general information on dirigible advertising and for specific dirigible projects. General scrapbooks have been arranged by date and are interspersed throughout the series and specific project scrapbooks have been arranged with the appropriate product/project file.
  - Report: Surveys Measuring the Effectiveness of Dirigible Advertising, by Alfred Politz Research, Inc., 1947; (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Report: Blimps in Industry (Off-Shore Oil Operations), by Richard G. Kopff, Jan. 1948 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Report: Study to Determine the Effectiveness of Sky Advertising, by Daniel Starch and Staff, May 1948 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1946 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Drawings for Advertisements, ca. 1940s-1950s; (5 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Photographs of Advertisement Ideas, ca. 1940s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Dirigibles, 1944 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Photographs of Leigh Sky Advertising Corp. Equipment, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, ca. 1940-1950s; (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Flamingo Foods Dirigible Project, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Ford Automobiles Dirigible Project (see also Box 14), 1947 (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Fort Pitt Beer Dirigible Project, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - Knickerbocker Beer Dirigible Project, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Reel 5846)
  - MGM (Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer) Dirigible Project, 1945-1950 (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - MGM Dirigible Scrapbook 5 (see Box 10), 1945-1950 (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - Duplicate Photos from MGM Dirigible Scrapbook 5, 1945-1950; (2 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - Mobiloil/ Flying Red Horse Dirigible Project (see also Box 14), 1947-1949; (7 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - Mobiloil/Flying Red Horse Dirigible Scrapbook 6, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - Mobiloil/Flying Red Horse Dirigible Scrapbook 7 (see Box 14), 1947-1949 (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - Mobiloil/Flying Red Horse Dirigible Scrapbook 8 (see Box 10), 1947-1949 (Box 9, Reel 5846)
  - Pfeiffer Beer Dirigible Project, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - R & H Beer Dirigible Project (see also Box 14), ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - Tydol Flying "A" Gasoline Dirigible Project, 1947-1949; (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - Tydol Flying "A" Gasoline Dirigible Scrapbook 9, 1947 (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - Tydol Flying "A" Gasoline Dirigible Scrapbook 10, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - Tydol Flying "A" Gasoline Dirigible Dirigible Scrapbook 11, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - Duplicate photographs from Tydol Flying "A" Gasoline Dirigible Scrapbooks, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Reel 5847)
  - MGM (Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer) Dirigible Scrapbook 5, 1945-1950 (Box 10, Reel 5846)
  - Mobiloil/Flying Red Horse Dirigible Scrapbook 8, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Reel 5846-5847)
  - Wonder Bread, 1947; (7 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5847)
  - Wonder Bread Dirigible Scrapbook 12 (see Box 14), 1947 (Box 11, Reel 5847)
  - Mobiloil/Flying Red Horse Dirigible Scrapbook 7, 1947-1949 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 7, 1947-1949 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Drawings for Ford Automobile Advertisements, 1947 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Photograph of Ford Automobile Dirigible on Runway, 1947 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Photograph of Ford Automobile Dirigible in Flight, 1947 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Artwork for Knickerbocker Beer, n.d. (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Poster for Knickerbocker Beer, n.d. (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Photograph of Mobiloil Dirigible on Runway, 1947-1949 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - Oversize Poster of R & H Beer Dirigible, n.d. (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5846-5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 1, 1946-1947 (Box 26 (sol), Reel 5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 2, 1947-1949 (Box 26 (sol), Reel 5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 3, 1947-1952 (Box 27 (sol), Reel 5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 4 (includes a photograph of Elizabeth Taylor), 1954 (Box 27 (sol), Reel 5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 6 (includes a photograph of Elizabeth Taylor), 1947-1949 (Box 28 (sol), Reel 5847)
  - General Dirigible Scrapbook 7 (see Box 14), 1947-1949 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5847)
- Urban Improvement Project Files, 1903-1992; Series 13; (Box 9, 14, 28-32, OV 34; 2.2 linear feet)
  This series consists of photographs, a promotion book, clippings, miscellaneous printed material, 18 scrapbooks, and individual project files that document the development of Leigh's urban improvement projects involving both the construction design of new buildings and the lighting of prominent buildings in New York City and elsewhere. Project files typically contain photographs, printed materials, notes, floorplans, blueprints, and scattered letters. The 18 consecutively numbered scrapbooks document both individual project files and general multiple projects. Scrapbooks containing material concerning multiple products have been numbered first.
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Buildings in New York City, 1980-1985 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Photograph File of Atlanta and New York, 1992; (7 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Promotion Book of Clippings and Photographs, 1984-1990 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - General Urban Improvement Scrapbook 1, 1957-1967; (8 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - General Urban Improvement Scrapbook 2 (see Box 28), 1962 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - General Urban Improvement Scrapbook 3 (see also Box 14), 1963-1969; (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Airline Terminal on Sixth Avenue Project, 1946 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Bank of Tokyo Building (100 Broadway) Project, 1981 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Chrysler Corporation Building Project, ca. 1964 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Claridge Building Project, ca. 1965 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Claridge Building Project Scrapbook 4 (see Box 28), ca. 1965 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Claridge Building Project Scrapbooks 5-6 (see Box 29), ca. 1965 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Convention Center Project, 1964 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - 42nd Street Renovation Project, ca. 1965 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Four Corners (Fifth Avenue and 57th Street) Project, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Garment District Building (South side of 42nd Street) Project Scrapbook 7 (see Box 29), 1961 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Grand Central Station Project (see Also OV 34), 1946-1965; (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Helmsley Building (230 Park Avenue) Project, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Helmsley Building (230 Park Avenue) Project Scrapbook 8 (see Box 30), 1980-1981 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Pan Am Building Project Scrapbook 9 (see Box 30), ca. 1967 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Port Authority Project Scrapbook 10 (see Box 31), ca. 1965 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Times Building/Allied Chemical Building Project, 1903-1965; (8 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Times Building/Allied Chemical Building Project Scrapbooks 11-12 (see Box 31), ca. 1960 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Times Building/Allied Chemical Building Project Scrapbooks 13-18 (see Box 32), April 1963-January 1965 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Baltimore Urban Improvement Project, Maryland National Bank, 1991 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - City of Reno Urban Improvement Project (see also Box 32), ca. 1964 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Cincinnati Urban Improvement Project File, Atrium I and II Lighting, 1988 (Box 9, Reel 5848)
  - Oversize pages from General Urban Improvement Scrapbook 3, 1963-1969 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Oversize photographs of the Times Building Project, 1903-1904 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Oversize photographs of Allied Chemical Building Project, ca. 1961 (Box 14 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - General Urban Improvement Scrapbook 2, 1962 (Box 28 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Claridge Building Project Scrapbook 4, ca. 1965 (Box 28 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Claridge Building Project Scrapbook 5-6, ca. 1965 (Box 29 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Garment District Building (South side of 42nd Street) Project Scrapbook 7, 1961 (Box 29 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Helmsley Building (230 Park Avenue) Project Scrapbook 8, 1980-1981 (Box 30 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Pan Am Building Project Scrapbook 9, ca. 1967 (Box 30 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Port Authority Project Scrapbook 10, ca. 1965 (Box 31 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Times Building/Allied Chemical Building Project Scrapbooks 11-12, ca. 1960 (Box 31 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Times Building/Allied Chemical Building Project Scrapbooks 13-18, April 1963-January 1965 (Box 32 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Oversized Photographs from City of Reno Urban Improvement Project, ca. 1964 (Box 32 (sol), Reel 5848)
  - Grand Central Station Project Oversized Drawings and Blueprints, 1946-1965 (Box OV 34, Reel 5848)